我们先说清楚  如果你要和我住
Just so we're clear, if you're gonna live with me,
你必须自给自足
you have to be self-sufficient.
我会尽力帮忙
I'll help however I can,
但我的作息时间很不正常
but my hours are a little crazy.
我没事的
I'll be fine.
-今年对你很重要  -我知道  你总这么说
- This is a big year for you. - I know. You keep saying that.
因为的确如此  大学论文怎么样了
Because it's true. How's the college essay coming?
我的导师说我应该谢谢作为拉丁裔的感受
My counselor said I should write about being a Latina.
-受到的阻碍  -这话题不错
- All the obstacles. - That's a good one.
我觉得简直胡扯  但这能帮我
I think it's BS, but if it'll help me
进西北大学或布朗大学  所以随便了
get into Northwestern or Brown, fine.
等等  你不觉得拉丁裔人会受到阻碍吗
Wait, you don't think there are obstacles for Latinos?
有啊  但我没有
I do, but not for me.
相信我  这个世界没你想象中的那么人人平等
Trust me. The world is not as color-blind as you think.
你为什么这么生气  我没有...
Why are you so mad? I don't--
我没有生气  我只是不想你忘记自己是谁
I'm not mad. I just don't want you to forget who you are
来自哪里  那...
and where you come from. That's--
电影还是下次看吧  走吧
We have to take a rain check on the movie, come on.
走吧
Come on, let's go.
待在车里  我马上回来
Stay in the car. I won't be long.
刚和凶案组的人谈过
Hey. Just talked to the homicide dicks.
流浪汉发现的  没有目击证人
Homeless guy found her, no witnesses.
安东尼奥  听说你回来了
Yo, Antonio, I heard you were back on the beat.
-你好吗  杰里  -比她好点
- How you doing, Jerry? - Better than her.
从她肚子里剖出毒品
Cut the drugs out of her gut
把她当垃圾似的扔在这里
and threw her away like a piece of trash.
欢迎来到美国
Welcome to America.
和锡那罗亚贩毒团伙的手法一样
Same M.O. as the Sinaloan Cartel.
他们会利用能吞食一千克毒品的年轻女性
They use young women that can swallow a key.
所以我联系了你们
That's why I texted you guys.
我可不希望外国毒骡出现在我的辖区
Foreign drug mule is the last thing I need on my books.
我们只是在跟进走私的线索
We're just following the smuggling angle.
不想惹上这一堆麻烦[垃圾]吧
Don't feel like picking up the trash, huh?
天啊
Oh, my God.
你在干什么  我要你待在车里的
What are you doing? I told you to stay in the car.
-她是谁  -不知道
- Who is she? - We don't know.
回去  你不该出来的
Come on. You can't be here.
他管她叫垃圾
He called her trash.
他说这个案子一团糟
He meant the case is trash.
因为她是拉丁裔的吗
Because she's Latina?
不  因为这个案子很难破
No! Because these cases are hard to solve.
快回去吧
Now come on.
但你还是会努力  不是吗
But you're still going to try, right?
伊娃  快回去
Eva, please.
你刚说我们有责任帮助拉丁裔人
You just said our job was to help other Latinos.
我们接了
We'll take it.
回去吧
Come on.
芝加哥
警署
第五季
第三集
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
无名女尸为拉丁裔  25到30岁
So our Jane Doe is Latina. Mid to late 20s.
指纹搜索无结果  数据库中没有匹配
Negative on the prints. Nothing in our databases.
翻译     小酸奶   风城章鱼X   不高兴童鞋
法医还在解剖尸体
M.E. is still processing the body.
但她是个毒骡
But it appears she was a drug mule?
翻译     小萝莉   H小欠   pang   圈圈
是的  他们取不出毒品
Yeah, and they had a problem recovering the product,
就把她当动物似的开膛破肚
so they gutted her like a farm animal.
货比运货人重要多了
Dope's worth more than the carriers.
校对     圈圈
初步估计死亡时间
Rigor puts time of death
在昨晚六点到八点之间
between 6:00 and 8:00 last night.
犯罪现场调查员在现场没找到多少血迹
Crime scene techs found very little blood on the scene,
时间轴     西查   chance-coco
所以她应该是在其他地方被杀  弃尸于此
so she was killed someplace else, and then dropped here.
为什么凶案组把这个案子给我们
Why's homicide passing this off on us?
后期     8T
我说我们要接
I said we'd take it.
总监     圈圈
凶案组肯定不想把这案子拱手送人吧
I bet Homicide was real sorry to see this one go.
好了
All right.
派警员搜查尸体被发现区域
All right, send out patrol to canvass the neighborhood
附近的地方
where the body was found.
调查摄像头  失踪人口
Check pod cameras, missing persons.
这个年轻女人不是凭空出现的
This young lady didn't just fall from the sky.
我有个深入毒贩团伙的线人
I got a C.I. deep in with these cartel guys.
很好  安东尼奥  伯吉斯
Good. Oh, Antonio, Burgess--
你们俩搭档行动
you two are gonna partner up now.
抢椅子游戏真好玩
It's a lovely game of musical chairs.
龙舌兰
Agave.
上班时间
I'm on duty.
古斯塔沃  听着  昨晚有一名毒骡被杀了
Gustavo, listen, a drug mule was murdered last night.
她被开膛破肚了
She was sliced open.
伙计  我已经不干那事了
Look, man, I'm not on the roster anymore, right?
我退出了  记得吗
I worked it off, remember?
但我还是要知道
I still need to know.
好吧  伙计  也许我的确
All right, man. Look, maybe I did hear
听说了些关于骡子的事
something about some mules.
洗耳恭听
I'm all ears.
但是首先  咱们来谈谈正事
But first, let's talk business.
让你女儿来和你一起住
Having your daughter come live with you,
这可不是小事
that's a big deal.
她和她妈妈  还有她妈妈的新男友
She and her mom-- and her mom's new boyfriend--
关系不是很好
they weren't getting along.
伊娃是个好孩子  成绩优异  排名顶尖
Eva's a good kid. Straight A's, top of her class.
我十七岁的时候简直是个噩梦
I was a nightmare when I was 17.
难以置信
I find that hard to believe.
真的
I was.
我...我很叛逆
I was a-- I was a rebel.
这辆车上是谁
Who's the bus?
你们看到了吗
Do you see what I see?
收到
Copy that.
所有人不要冲动
Everybody take it easy.
先别行动  先别行动
Just hold. Just hold.
好了  行动
All right, move in.
上
Go.
-上上上  -21E  紧急情况
- Go! Go! Go! - This is 21 Eddie, emergency!
-派救护车来科玛路5500号  -上
- Ambulance to 5500 Kolmar! - Go!
快点
Come on!
这要看你怎么决定了  哥们
I mean it's really your call, bro.
听说你和我哥哥合作行动
Heard you're working with my brother.
是的  目前为止还行
Yeah. So far, so good.
才没几天  但是...
It's only been a few days, but--
你好  我想问你几个问题  好吗
Hi, I'm just gonna ask you a few questions, okay?
你认识她吗
Do you recognize her?
她怕进监狱
She's afraid to go to jail.
她说她是被迫吞下毒品
She says she was forced to swallow
来偿还她的债务
drugs to pay off her coyote.
告诉她如果她合作
Okay, tell her if she cooperates,
我们会争取把贩毒罪名减免的
we'll see if we can get the criminal drug charges reduced.
她不认得那个女的
She doesn't recognize the woman,
但她确定她不是个毒骡
but she's certain she's not a drug mule.
-她怎么知道  -她年龄太大
- How does she know? - She's too old.
给贩毒团伙干活的毒骡都是十五六岁
The drug mules that work for this gang are 15 or 16.
明白了  多谢
Got it. Thank you.
威利  你接的那个女的
So, Willy, the woman you were going to pick up,
肚子里装了一公斤海洛因
she had a key of heroin in her gut.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
但我只是接她一程而已
But I was just gonna give her a ride.
是吗  你接她上这种路吗
Yeah? Were you gonna give her this kind of ride?
不是不是
Whoa. No, no.
这跟我可没关系
I had nothing to do with that.
你们什么都证明不了
No way you could prove it.
我们能证明的东西怕吓着你
Oh, you'd be surprised what we can prove.
尤其是道上传出风声
Especially when it gets leaked
说你给我们提供情报
that you've been feeding us information.
可我什么都没说
But I'm not.
这话就等你被我们扔出去之后
You probably ought to tell that to your bosses
跟你老板说吧
after we toss you.
他们肯定很讲理的
I'm sure they're reasonable men.
我接她们去旅馆  给她们吃泻药
I take them to hotels, give them laxatives,
等毒包出来就完事了
and wait for the balloons to come.
我就做这些
That's all I do.
只不过有时候没时间等她们拉出来  是不是
Except sometimes they don't when clock's ticking, right?
值十多万的毒品
Got $100,000 worth of heroin
就这么困在一个无名姑娘的肚子里
stuck in some nameless girl's belly.
干脆直接开膛破肚
Why not just slice her open?
那也不是这么切的
Wouldn't happen like that.
不是吗  那该是怎么样
No? How would it happen?
换个方向切
Cut the other way.
毒包在这里  不能横着割
Drugs are here. You don't slice across.
而是竖着割开  把毒取出来
You slice down, then take them out.
她不是毒骡
She's not a mule.
根据那个女孩的说法  毒骡都十五六岁
According to the girl, all the mules are around 15.
而死者看起来快三十了
The DOA looks closer to 30.
如果她肚子里有毒的话
And if there were drugs inside her,
他们显然也会竖着切  而不是横着
they would've cut down, not across, apparently.
你知道贩毒集团还不会做什么吗
You know what else the cartel doesn't do?
强奸毒骡
Rape drug mules.
刚收到法医报告
Just got the M.E. Report.
死者阴部有严重的撕裂伤
The DOA had significant vaginal tearing
死因也是掐死的
and the cause of death was strangulation.
所以这肚子上的横切口呢
So the slice across her stomach?
肯定是犯案之后做的
Must've been done after the fact.
你是说有人奸杀了她
You're saying that someone raped her, killed her,
又切开她肚子  做成毒骡的样子
cut her open to make it look like she was a mule?
谁会在乎一个无名的拉丁裔运毒者呢
Who's gonna cry over some anonymous Latina drug runner?
巡警刚刚在一条巷子里找到了血衣
Patrol just found bloody clothes in an alley
就在遗体丢弃处附近
near where the body was dumped.
出发
Hit it.
多谢
Thanks.
加西亚  加西亚
Garcia. Garcia, hey.
你好啊  金  别走太近
What's up, Kim? Don't come too close.
我臭得像是在27个垃圾箱里打过滚
The reason I smell like I've been in 27 dumpsters
是因为我真这么做了
is because I have been.
我提醒过你巡警不好当
I warned you about the rookie life.
来
Come on.
在托马的追悼会上看到你了
Saw you at Toma's memorial.
是啊  事情真是太疯狂了
Yeah, that whole thing's crazy.
真不敢相信他不在了
Can't believe he's really gone.
有什么发现
All right, what do we got?
一件沾血的女性衣服
All right, a woman's bloody clothes.
在离死者被丢弃地点两个街区外找到的
Found them two blocks down from the DOA.
你没碰什么吧
You didn't touch anything, did you?
没有  只是拍了照片  就联系了你们
No, just took some photos, and then I called you.
很好  我来看看
Great. I'll look.
来看看这个  格洛莉亚·莫拉莱斯
Check this out. Gloria Morales.
肯定是从口袋里掉出来的
Must've fallen out of the pocket.
身份证是假的  但地址没准是真的
It's a fake ID, but it might be right address.
-干得漂亮  加西亚  -多谢
- Good job, Garcia. - Thanks.
法律又没规定他们要有证件才能租房
There's no law they need papers to rent an apartment.
我们知道  女士  她在这住多久了
We know that, Senora. How long has she lived here?
-半年  -哪张床是她的
- Six months. - Which bed is hers?
那张
That one.
看起来像是血迹
This looks like blood.
装好取证留存吧
Let's make sure to get those into evidence.
格洛莉亚提过有人威胁她吗
Did Gloria ever mention being threatened?
没对我说过  她话不多
No, not to me. She kept to herself.
没事
It's okay.
你是谁
Who are you?
那是她儿子
That's her son.
奥斯卡  我是普拉特警长
Oscar, I'm Sergeant Platt.
不过如果你愿意  也可以叫我特鲁迪
You can call me Trudy if you want though, okay?
你饿了吗
You hungry?
那么奥斯卡  我们这样吧
So, Oscar. Here's the deal.
等我们给你找好去处之前  你就在这住着
You're gonna be here until we figure out where you should go.
希望能送你去亲戚家  你在这边有亲人吗
Hopefully a relative. Do you have family here?
你怎么不跟我说话呢
Why won't you talk to me?
我妈妈不让我和警察说话
My mama told me never to talk to the police.
明白
Got you.
格洛莉亚·莫拉莱斯  来自危地马拉
All right. Gloria Morales, she came from Guatemala
半年前带着儿子奥斯卡一起来的
six months ago with her son Oscar.
没有入境记录  所以肯定是非法入境
There's no border crossing, so she entered here illegally.
房东认为她在某家工厂上班
Landlady thought she worked at some factory.
说她交房租挺及时的
Said she paid her rent on time.
我们走访了街坊邻居
We canvassed the neighborhood.
没人愿意开口
Nobody wanted to talk.
他们都吓坏了
Yeah, they're freaked out.
他们认为带警徽的都是抓他们驱逐出境的
They think anybody with a badge is trying to deport them.
话说法医检测了垃圾箱里发现的血衣
Hey, so the M.E. ran those clothes from the dumpster.
垃圾箱里的血迹和死者完全匹配
Now the blood in the dumpster definitely matches our DOA,
但在衣服上也找不到别的证据了
but they couldn't find any other evidence on the clothes.
那她住处那件牛仔裤的血迹呢
What about the blood on the jeans in the apartment?
那处血迹来自一头猪
That blood matches a pig. Yeah.
准确点说是猪牛羊血的混合  不管你们信不信
More precisely pig, cow, and lamb, believe it or not.
也许她在餐厅工作
Maybe she worked at a restaurant?
我搜索了她住处的那张公交卡
Okay, I ran the old bus card that we found at the apartment.
她每天搭127班蓝线去西区132号
She took the 127 Blue Line every day to West 132nd.
那就把西区132号周边一英里内的所有门店
All right, so let's run every business within a mile radius
都查一遍
of West 132nd.
找出她工作的地方
Let's find out where she worked.
西区132号附近只有一家大型公司
There's only one large company around West 132nd.
布考斯基肉食包装公司
It's Bukowski Meat Packing Company.
主要产品为羊肉猪肉牛肉
They specialize in lamb, pig, and cow products.
地面部队  前往工厂
Boots on the ground. Hit that factory.
警察
Policia!
格洛莉亚·莫拉莱斯  她是不是在这里工作
Gloria Morales! Did she work here?
听着  我们不会逮捕任何人的
Hey, look. We're not here to arrest anybody.
麻烦你们帮帮忙
Just help us out.
格洛莉亚·莫拉莱斯  你认识她吗
Okay. Gloria Morales. Do you know her?
-格洛莉亚·莫拉莱斯  -没人认识吗
- Gloria Morales. - Nope? Anyone?
你认得她吗
You recognize her?
你呢  你认识她吗
How about you? Did you know her?
你认识她吗
Hey. Did you know her?
我只想知道是不是出了什么事
I just want to know if something happened.
不如我们去个别的地方
Yeah, well, why don't we go somewhere
私下聊聊吧
we can talk in private?
我不能去
No, I can't.
他们是不会跟你们说话的
They're not going to talk to you.
他们害怕警察
They're scared of cops.
你认识她吗
Do you know her?
不认识  抱歉
No. Sorry.
你们这么闯进来
Hey! What the hell are you guys doing
是想干什么
barging in here like this?
你们进来是要换衣服的
You gotta be frocked to be in here.
我会丢掉工作的
I'm gonna get fined!
好了  都回去工作  不许说话了
All right, everybody back to work! Basta!
行了  休息时间结束  你们跟我过来
That's it! Break's over! Come on, come with me.
格洛莉亚·莫拉莱斯  她在这里工作
Gloria Morales. She worked here.
我这有300名员工  都戴面具
I got 300 employees. They all wear masks.
迈克尔
Michael!
那是我儿子  迈克尔
Here's my son, Michael.
-你认识这个女人吗  -不认识
- You know this woman? - No.
我可能在切割流水线上见过她
I might've seen her on the cutting line.
她昨晚被人谋杀了
She was murdered last night.
-我的天啊  -太可怕了
- Oh my God. - That's awful.
很遗憾听到这个消息
I'm sorry to hear that.
联系她的家人
Get in touch with her family.
告诉他们我们会负担全部丧葬费
Let them know that we'll cover all the funeral costs.
根据职业安全与卫生条例管理局记录  过去两年
According to OSHA records, you've been fined 17 times
你这里曾17次被发现违反工作安全规定
in the last two years for unsafe workplace violations.
-罚款我们都交了  -别插嘴
- We paid all the fines. - I'll do the talking.
英语专业的
English major, doesn't know
还不懂商业运作
that much about business. Not yet.
说到这个罚款  我们已经尽力遵守
As for the fines, we do our best to comply
那成百上千条毫无意义的规范要求
with thousands of meaningless regulations,
但偶尔我们也会在这项高尚的追求上出点问题
and from time to time we fall short of this noble objective.
还有别的事吗
Anything else?
我明白  你雇佣非法劳工
You know, I get it. You hire undocumented workers.
他们拿着最低的工资干着最苦的活
They do the worst jobs for the worst pay,
还不能多说一句话  对不对
and keep their mouths shut, right?
移民不就是这样的吗  朋友
That's how immigrants make it, my friend.
他们做别人不愿做的工作
They do the jobs that other people don't want to do.
你知道吗
And you know what?
能有这份工作他们就很开心了
They're thrilled to have the work.
只要你良心过得去就行
If that's what helps you sleep.
如果你们没有搜查令
Look, if you don't have a warrant,
可不可以请你们离开
would you please leave?
把布考斯基的所有事都挖出来
Dig up everything we can on Bukowski,
查查他昨晚的不在场证明
and run his alibi for last night.
你觉得他真的会是嫌犯吗
Do you think he's a legitimate person of interest?
他真的是一个混蛋  这是事实
He's a legitimate prick, that's for sure.
等等
Hold on.
你介不介意我问你几个问题  拜托
Do you mind if I talk to you, por favor?
我知道你知道格洛莉亚的事
Look, you know something about Gloria, I know it.
她是我妹妹
She's my sister.
出什么事了吗
Did something happen?
你们为什么要问问题
Why are you asking questions?
你妹妹昨晚被人谋杀了
Your sister was murdered last night.
不是吧
No.
-这不可能  -节哀
- No, no. - I'm so sorry.
她昨晚没回家  我就知道了
I knew it, when she didn't come home.
你叫什么名字  你叫什么
What's your name? What's your name?
露西亚
Lucia.
露西亚  请跟我们来
Lucia, please come with us.
我们真的需要你的帮助
We really need your help.
-我不能去  -真的没事的
- No, I can't. - No, look, it's okay.
我们不在乎你是不是合法移民
I mean, we don't care if you don't have papers.
我们只想找出杀害格洛莉亚的凶手
We just want to find out who hurt Gloria.
我侄子在哪里
Where's my nephew?
如果你跟我来  我可以带你见他
If you come with me, I can show you.
-好  -来吧
- Okay. - Okay.
普拉特  这位是...
Platt, this is--
-大姨  -奥斯卡
- Tia! - Oscar!
奥斯卡  你还好吗  你还好吗
Oscar! Estas bien? Estas bien?
-我刚和儿童与家庭服务部联系过  -怎么说
- I just talked to DCFS. - Yeah?
他们要把奥斯卡送去集体家庭
They're going to put Oscar in a group home.
为什么他不能和他大姨一起住
No. Why can't he go with his aunt?
她是非法移民  所以我们会有
She's illegal, which means we gotta jump through
很多新困难
a bunch of new hoops.
他们那边能拖多久拖多久
Hold them off as long as you can.
我去找找我在那边工作的朋友
Let me talk to a friend who works over there.
好  我尽力
Okay. I'll do my best.
你昨晚有没有看到格洛莉亚跟谁说话
Did you see Gloria talking to anybody last night?
没有  我上白班  她上晚班
No. I work days, she works nights.
我基本上见不到她
I almost never see her.
你认不认识什么人
Is there anyone you know
想要伤害你妹妹格洛莉亚
that wanted to hurt your sister Gloria?
不好意思  我不能告诉你们
I'm sorry, I can't tell you what you want.
露西亚  你在怕谁
Lucia, who are you afraid of?
是你们公司的老板吗  还是别的什么人
Is it the owners of the company? Someone else?
我要确定奥斯卡没事
I need to make sure Oscar is okay.
我可以照顾他
That I can take care of him.
我们可以在这里一起生活
That we can stay here as a family.
我们会尽全力帮助你们
Look, we will do everything in our power
达成心愿
to make that happen.
但请你告诉我们你知道的情况
But please, tell us what you know.
我会保护你的
I will protect you.
我发誓
I promise.
我跟格洛莉亚说了不要和他约会
I told Gloria not to go out with him.
但她就是不听
But she wouldn't listen!
当她想分手的时候
When she tried to break it off,
他根本不同意
he wouldn't take no for an answer.
他变得咄咄逼人  威胁她
He got aggressive. Made threats.
是谁
Who was it?
没事的  是谁
It's okay. Who was it?
-芝加哥警署  -大家都别动
- Chicago PD. - Everybody stay where you are.
-你要干嘛  -找你儿子
- What do you want? - Your son.
找我儿子干嘛
My son? For what?
他说不认识格洛莉亚·莫拉莱斯是撒谎
He lied about knowing Gloria Morales.
我们想知道原因
We want to know why.
我们还需要你所有员工的
And we want the names and phone numbers
-姓名和电话  -可以
- of all your employees. - Sure.
只要你给我看搜查令
Soon as you show me a search warrant.
早上就会给到你
I'll have them for you in the morning.
我们走
Let's go.
律师到之前什么都别说  迈克尔  别说
Not a word 'till the lawyers get there, Michael. Not a word.
没事  是个大误会
It's nothing. It's a big misunderstanding.
英语专业
English major?
打赌你没想过最后还是会
Bet you never thought you'd wind up
回到家族生意上来吧
back in the family business.
我父亲让我等律师来
My father instructed me to wait for the lawyer.
你也并不总是
Mm-hmm. Well, you don't always do
听爸爸的  对吧
what Daddy says, do you?
你是按自己想法行事  随自己的开心来
I mean do things your own way. Follow your bliss.
也许就把你和格洛莉亚之间的事保密了  对吧
Probably kept your romance with Gloria secret, right?
因为从我的理解看
I mean, 'cause from what I understand,
你爸爸并不会让你随心所欲
your dad is not really a follow your bliss kind of guy.
我们知道你们约会过几次
We know you two went out a few times.
对  我很喜欢她
Yeah, I liked her a lot.
她美丽  聪明  坚强
Oh, she was beautiful. Smart. Strong.
她在这个国家待了半年
I mean, here she is, in this country six months,
有勇气和你父亲对抗
and she has the courage to fight your old man.
想让工作环境更安全
To make the work conditions safer.
我知道  这就是我
Yeah, I know. And that's what
试着帮她的  但是
I was trying to help her with, but--
你害怕你父亲
You were afraid of your father.
-你不...  -没事  你喜欢她
- You don't... - It's okay. You liked her.
欣赏她  然后呢
Admired her. Then what?
我没有杀她
I didn't kill Gloria!
但她没有回应你的感情  这让你很困扰
But she didn't feel the same way, and that bothered you.
-我明白  -我真的
- I get it. - You know, I really--I--
我要等律师来
I need to wait for the lawyer.
迈克尔
Michael--
我要等律师来
I need to wait for the lawyer.
要我说  就给他施加压力
I say we keep the pressure on him.
这种小孩在牢房里待48小时  肯定崩溃
A kid like this spends 48 hours in a cell, he'll break.
好  先关着他  但我们需要更多证据  得快
All right, I'll hold him, but we need more evidence, fast.
和伯吉斯回工厂
So grab Burgess, head back to the plant.
肯定有人看到过什么或听到过什么
Somebody had to see something, or hear something, okay?
继续为她声援
Just keep banging the drum.
我们是警察  并不歧视移民
We're city police, we don't care about immigration,
也不在意绿卡什么的
green cards, any of that.
博伊特  我们有麻烦了
Voight, we have a problem.
移民海关总署
对  我们刚接到匿名电话
Yeah, we just got an anonymous call.
我是芝加哥警署的道森警探  发生什么事了
Detective Dawson, Chicago PD. What's going on here?
我们得到消息  这里的员工没有签过用工协议
We got a tip about undocumented workers.
我们在调查这里一个员工的谋杀案
Listen, we are investigating a murder of an employee.
我们得和他们谈谈
We need to talk to these people.
抱歉  我们服从华盛顿州的指示
Sorry, we take our orders from Washington.
-按指示处理  -安东尼奥  她在那儿
- Proceed as ordered. - Antonio, there she is!
-露西亚  -他们要把我带去哪里
- Lucia! - Where are they taking me?
-没事的  -你撒谎
- It's gonna be fine. - You lied!
你说过不会这样的
You said this wouldn't happen!
是你举报的
This was you!
你猜对了
You're damn right it was.
你把自己的员工出卖给警方
You dropped a dime on your own employees?
这叫主动报警
It's called self-reporting.
不不  这叫削弱目击证人
Oh, no, no, no, no, it's called witness tampering.
我儿子与格洛莉亚·莫拉莱斯的死无关
My son had nothing to do with Gloria Morales' death.
-他没这个胆子  -不像他父亲
- He doesn't have what it takes. - Unlike his old man.
什么  现在我成凶手了
What? Now I'm the killer?
如果不是你儿子  下一个嫌疑人就是你
Well, if it wasn't your son, you're next on the list.
格洛莉亚计划提起诉讼
Gloria was planning on filing a lawsuit.
我猜那惹恼了你
I'm guessing that pissed you off.
你真觉得我会为了这种没胜算的诉讼
You really think I'm gonna risk all of this
冒这些风险吗
for some half-assed lawsuit?
我有保险的  快滚蛋吧
I got insurance for that! Now get the hell out of here.
警长  移民海关总署刚逮捕了露西亚·莫拉莱斯
Sarge, I.C.E. just grabbed up Lucia Morales
-还有其他20多个工人  -我听说了
- and about 20 other workers. - I heard.
等等  我去州检察官办公室
Wait. I talked to my old boss
和以前的上司说了
at the State's Attorney's office.
他很怕卷进去  他说这是敏感话题
He's afraid to get involved. Sensitive issue, he said.
政府的人只是按规矩办事
Look, the feds are just doing their job.
不管你站在哪一边
Whatever side of this thing you're on,
这些人是不合法的
these people are here illegally.
我答应过她  我看着她的眼睛
I promised her. I looked her in the eye
告诉她  我会保护她
and told her I'd protect her.
那这事很难兑现了  老兄
That's a tough check to cash, bro.
不该这样的
Well, it shouldn't be.
这座城市是个避难所
I mean this is a sanctuary city.
我们甚至都不能去问移民的情况
We're not even allowed to ask about immigration status.
但我怎么知道那老家伙会跟政府
Now how did I know the old man was gonna call the feds
出卖自己的员工
on his own workers?
你问我  我可以告诉你这完全合理
Well, you ask me, it makes perfect sense.
他想保护自己的儿子
I mean, he's trying to protect his son.
我尽力而为吧
I'll see what I can do.
我查了迈克尔·布考斯基的不在场证明
I ran Michael Bukowski's alibi.
他从6点半到9点都在饥渴老鸦酒吧
He was at the Thirsty Raven from 6:30 till 9:00,
和他自己说的一样
just like he said.
鉴证科已经查了
I mean the crime techs already went through
他的房间和车子
his room and his car.
目前我们甚至无法把迈克尔和格洛莉亚联系在一起
So far, we can't even connect Michael to Gloria.
-他父亲呢  -他的说辞也无懈可击
- What about the father? - His story's pretty tight too.
他整晚和老婆待在家
He was at home all night, with his wife.
有监控录像可以证明
He's got video surveillance to back it up.
-露西亚那边有突破吗  -没有
- Any luck with Lucia? - Nope.
她在被遣返回瓜地马拉的飞机上
She's on a plane back to Guatemala.
什么  等等  你说过会找人帮忙的
What? Wait, you said you were going to talk to someone.
原来露西亚3年前就被驱逐了
Turns out Lucia was deported three years ago.
非法回来  这是重罪
Came back illegally, which is a felony.
自动遣返
Automatic deportation.
我尽力了
I tried.
有新证据吗
Okay, any new evidence?
好  别管布考斯基那孩子了  我们没证据
Okay, kick the Bukowski kid. We got nothing on him.
别人的证据也没有
Or anyone else, for that matter.
下次再从凶案组手上接案子
Next time you grab a case from Homicide,
先确定这个案子我们能破
let's make sure it's one we can solve.
家事法庭的判决  最下面签字
It's the family court order. Sign at the bottom.
为什么我不能跟大姨走
Why can't I go with my aunt?
你大姨得先回家一下
Your aunt had to go back home for a while,
这些人真的都很和善
but these are really nice people
他们会好好照顾你的
and they're going to take very good care of you.
我不想上那辆车
I don't want to go in that van!
我知道  宝贝
I understand, honey.
但现在我也没办法
But there's nothing I can do about that right now.
我不想进去
I don't want to go in there!
奥斯卡  怎么回事
Oscar, what's the matter?
我妈妈上了一辆这样的车就再也没回来
My mama went into a van like that, and she never came back.
一  二  三  很好
One, two, three. Okay, good.
现在  奥斯卡  我们一起回想一下
Now, Oscar, we're going to go over
那天晚上发生的所有事  好吗
everything you remember about that night, okay?
我妈妈亲了亲我  然后就去上班了
My mama gave me a kiss, and then she went to work.
她把你一个人留在家里吗
She leaves you alone?
我大姨到家她才走
Only until my Tia gets home.
你说她上了一辆车
You said she got into a van.
我每天晚上都从窗口看着她出门
I watch her out the window every night.
她跟一个男人一起走了
She went with a man.
你记得他长什么样吗
Do you remember what he looked like?
他是拉丁裔  胖胖的  秃头
He was Latino, fat, bald.
再看到他你能认出来吗
Would you recognize him if you saw him again?
记不记得那辆车是什么样的
Remember anything else about the van?
上面有一头奶牛
It had a cow on it.
布考斯基
我儿子不在这里
My son's not here.
我们找的是别人
We're looking for someone else.
意思是他洗脱嫌疑了吗
Does that mean he's no longer a suspect?
目前没有  但我们得跟你的一个司机谈谈
Not at the moment, but we need to talk to one of your drivers.
那辆车上有你们的商标
A van with your logo on
格洛莉亚·莫拉莱斯被杀那晚
it was spotted outside Gloria Morlaes' apartment
那辆车在她公寓楼下停过
on the night she was murdered.
司机据说是个胖子  拉丁裔  秃头
Now, the driver was described as overweight, Latino, and bald.
有  真有这么个人叫洛佩斯...
Yeah, actually a guy named Lopez--
弗兰克·洛佩斯在哪里
Hey, where's Frank Lopez?
他两个小时前开着车走了
He took out his van two hours ago.
好的  我们需要车型和车牌号
Okay, we need the model and license plate right away.
他有电话吗
Does he have a phone?
我一直在给他打电话  但是没人接
I've been trying to call him, but no answer.
好的  有储物柜吗
All right, what about a locker?
有  里面
Yeah, inside.
好  快走  快走
All right. Come on, come on.
凯文  是我  嫌犯开白色货车
Kev, it's me. The suspect's driving a white van.
上面有布考斯基的商标  车牌号K94F77
Bukowski logo on it, license plate is King-9-4-Frank-7-7.
布考斯基
想找一辆画着奶牛的白色货车应该不难
It can't be that hard to find a white van with a cow on it.
他可能已经在去佛罗里达或墨西哥的路上了
He's probably halfway to Florida or Mexico.
货车在特兰波5600街停过
All right, van was spotted. 5600 block of Trumbo.
-我就说吧  -是的  长官
- Well, like I said. - Yes, sir.
什么鬼
What the hell?
等等
Wait.
好了  上
Okay, go.
芝加哥警察
Chicago PD!
这是因为被偷的货车吗
Is this about the stolen truck?
-因为格洛莉亚·莫拉莱斯  -谁
- It's about Gloria Morales. - Who's she?
我们一起走一趟  也许能唤醒你的记忆
Why don't we go for a ride? Maybe it will jog your memory.
我在送货  钥匙就插在车上
I was making a delivery, left my keys inside.
太尴尬了
You know, I was so embarrassed.
以前从没发生过这种事
Nothing like that's every happened to me before.
-我打电话报警了  你们可以查  -查了
- I called 911. You can check. - We did.
为什么不打电话给你老板
Why didn't you call your boss?
我是希望你们可以把车找回来
Well, I was hoping you guys would find it
这样我就不用告诉他了
before I had to tell him.
也许你是想毁掉能证明
Maybe you were trying to destroy the evidence
你跟格洛莉亚·莫拉莱斯有关的证据
linking you to Gloria Morales.
我们在厂里跟你聊过
Come on, we talked to you at the plant.
你撒谎了  你说你不认识她
You lied. You said you didn't know her.
我没认出来是她
I didn't recognize her.
你用公司的车带过她
You gave her a ride in that company van.
我们有目击证人看到两天前你和格洛莉亚一起
We have a witness that saw you with Gloria two nights ago.
我经常非法载人
I give lots of illegals rides.
他们的人生太悲惨了
They have such a hard life, you know?
你在墨西哥出生
You were born in Mexico.
我还在襁褓里就来了
I came over when I was a baby.
我是正当途径过来的
I did it the right way.
-好吧  -我拿到了文件  成了合法公民
- Okay! - I got my papers, and became a citizen.
我是美国人
I'm an American!
你也是谋杀图森一个女性移民的
You're also a person of interest in the murder
嫌疑犯
of an immigrant woman from Tucson.
没有证据
There's no evidence.
这是什么  什么意思
What's all this? What's that mean?
和平
Peace.
你还真是一个和平宁静的人啊
You're a real peaceful guy, huh?
是的
That's right.
说吧  你为什么这么恨你们自己人
Tell me, why do you hate your own people so much?
他们不是自己人
They're not my people.
他们是非法移民的外国人
They're illegal aliens.
他们违法  抢我们的工作
They break our laws and take our jobs.
他们令我的人生更加悲惨  他们没把它变好
They make my life worse; they don't make it better.
如果她留在她该在的地方
And if she would have stayed where she belonged,
她自己的国家  她就不会死了
in her own country, she'd still be alive!
如果她没有认识你  她也不会死
If she never met you, she'd still be alive.
好了  走吧
Come on, let's go.
不知道你有没有收到提示
I don't know if you got the memo,
我们的一举一动都在大哥的监视之下
but big brother's watching everything we do.
那畜生是个杀人犯
Yeah, well, that son of a bitch is a killer.
可能你没错  但我们没有证据
Yeah, you may be right, but we got no evidence.
死者身上  货车上都找不到能匹配的DNA
There's no DNA match on the woman or the van.
因为他把车子炸掉了
Because he blew it up.
我知道  哥们  你悠着点
I get it! Bro, you gotta slow down.
什么意思
What does that mean?
我什么意思
What do I mean?
目前我们审讯出来的唯一结果就是
So far the only thing we've gotten out of this investigation
20个无辜的人被驱逐出境了
20 innocent people deported.
你和厄普顿现在去陈尸间
you and Upton head down to the morgue,
看看是否有其他的受害者
see if there are any other Jane Doe victims
被以同样错误的方式切开
cut open the same wrong way, okay?
-现在就去  -听我说
- On it. - All right, look.
带上鲁塞克和伯吉斯  再次调查
Grab Ruzek, Burgess. Recanvass the neighborhood
格洛莉亚住所的邻居  也就找到她尸体的地方
where Gloria lived, and where her body was found.
这次带着洛佩兹的照片一起过去
This time, get Lopez's picture out there too.
这两具尸体符合描述
These two fit the description.
一个六个月之前被杀  一个是三个月之前
Killed six months ago and three months ago.
都是拉丁裔  都是腹部
Both Latina, both sliced horizontally
-被横向切开  -同一把武器吗
- along the abdomen. - Same weapon?
同一种刀  非常锋利  伤口干净利落
Same type of knife. Extremely sharp, clean wound.
像是屠夫的刀
Like a butcher's blade.
你之前说过还有一个人符合描述对吗
You said there was another woman who fit the description?
是的  她一年之前被火化了
Yeah, she was cremated a year ago.
你有她的遗物吗
Do you have any personal effects?
应该是有的
I think so.
凶杀案的警探根本不想收集它们
Homicide detectives never bothered to collect them.
这些属于哪个女人
Which women did these belong to?
莫妮卡·德尔加多  那个被火化的人的
Monica Delgado, the one who was cremated.
你还有她的照片吗
Do you still have her photos?
我查一下
Let me check.
你知道她们是在哪里被发现的吗
Do you by any chance know where these women were found?
一个被发现在16街和凯基街的垃圾桶里
One was found in a dump near 16th and Kedzie.
另外两个在小村镇的某个工业园区里
The other two in some industrial park in Little Village.
我们去查查这张地铁卡
Let's run with the subway pass.
月票
-是的  -谢谢
- Yeah. - Thank you.
-不客气  -谢谢
- You're welcome. - Thank you.
不好意思  你认识他吗
Excuse me, do you recognize him?
-不  -不认识吗
- Nope. - No?
先生  我是警察  你认识他吗
Sir? Police. Do you recognize this guy?
-不  -她呢
- No. - What about her?
-她死了吗  -你认识她
- She's dead? - You recognize her?
我不知道她的名字
I don't know her name,
但是我以前在18街和阿什兰街附近看过她
but I used to see her hanging out on 18th and Ashland.
好的  谢谢你
Great. Thank you.
谢谢  能告诉我们你的联系方式吗
Thank you. Can we get your information?
如果可以写下你的名字  地址  电话
If you could write down your name, address, phone number...
金  我是杰  你们在皮尔森街附近对吗
Kim, it's Jay. You guys are down near Pilsen, right?
再看看  你确定你不认识她吗
Look again. You're sure you've never seen her?
真的不认识  我们可以走了吗
Definitely not. Could we go?
好吧
Yeah.
今天的社区出警就当到这里吧
So much for community policing.
好吧
Yeah.
值得一试
Worth a shot.
打扰了  我们是芝加哥警署的警察
Excuse me. We're with Chicago PD.
我们来打听几天前被杀的一名女性的事
We're here about a young woman who was killed a few days ago?
你认识她吗
Do you recognize her?
我不认识
No, I don't.
等等  怎么了  你可以相信我们
Wait, what is it? You can trust us.
他们也杀了我侄女
They killed my niece too.
那是一年前的事了
It was a year ago.
她刚来几个月
She had only been here for a few months.
-她叫什么  -莫妮卡
- What's her name? - Monica.
他们割开了她的肚子
They sliced her belly.
你的侄女有其他的工作吗
Did your niece have another job?
是的  她在皮尔森街的一家肉场清理机器
Yeah, she was cleaning machines at the meat plant in Pilsen.
-布考斯基屠宰场  -是的
- Bukowski Meat Packing. - That's right.
她说有一个人一直想要载她出去兜风
She said there was a man who kept wanting to give her a ride.
一直缠着她
He wouldn't leave her alone.
等等  你认识他吗
Wait, do you recognize him?
我没见过他  但是莫妮卡说他是胖子而且秃顶
I never saw him, but Monica said he was fat and bald.
他有一串写着Paz的项链
And he had a necklace that said "Paz."
"Paz"就像是和平
"Paz" Like peace.
她就是这么说的
That's what she said.
所以你们没报警吗
So you didn't tell the police?
我怕  我们来这里21年了
I was afraid. We've been here 21 years,
但是实际上是黑户
but we don't have papers.
姨妈  为什么在和他们说话
Tia, why you talking to them?
基科  他们是为你妹妹的事来的
Chico, they're here about your sister.
现在才来吗  都过了这么久了
Now? After all this time, right?
我们想知道你的妹妹发生了什么
Look, we just want to find out what happened to your sister.
是啊  她死了  一切都结束了
Yeah, well, she's dead, so it's over.
也许我们可以挖出尸体看看有没有什么线索
Maybe we can exhume the body. See if there's any evidence.
-总有一些可以  -不  不可能了
- There's things that we can-- - No, you don't get it.
我们把骨灰倒入了密歇根湖里
We dumped her ashes over Lake Michigan.
现在我的姨妈不会再说别的了
Now, my aunt, she's done talking.
我们只是想找到杀害你妹妹的凶手
Look, we just want to find the man that killed your sister.
-是的  相信我  -我也想  走吧
- Yeah, trust me. - So do I. Come on.
莫妮卡和格洛莉亚都在
And Monica and Gloria both worked
布考斯基肉场工作过
at the Bukowski Meat Packing Plant,
莫妮卡告诉她姨妈有一个人跟踪她
and Monica told her aunt that the guy that was stalking her
他带着一个写着"Paz"的项链
wore a necklace that said "Paz,"
就像洛佩兹戴的那条一样
just like the one Lopez wore.
你做检测了吗
You ran this?
-是的  上面没证据  -她姨妈没见过洛佩兹吗
- Yeah, it's clean. - And the aunt never saw Lopez?
没有
No.
所以我们没有指向洛佩兹的DNA证据
So we got no DNA to link Lopez,
也没有凶器和目击证人
we got no murder weapon, no eyewitnesses.
只有道听途说的证据
All we got is hearsay testimony.
我们还有那个孩子  奥斯卡
And we got the kid. Oscar.
他可以证明洛佩兹在他妈妈被杀的晚上
I mean, he can put Lopez with his mother
和她妈妈在一起
the night she was murdered.
如果孩子能指认嫌犯
If the kid can make a positive ID,
那我们就可以开始立案调查
then we can start to build a case,
可以拿到搜查令  但是没有的话
we can get warrants, but short of that,
我们只能放了洛佩兹
we're gonna have to let Lopez walk.
听着
Listen...
我们只有一次机会将他绳之以法
We got one chance to nail this guy.
我在想要不要冒险
I figured why take any chances?
什么意思
Meaning?
这个孩子十岁
The kid is ten.
他会紧张的
He's gonna be nervous.
奥斯卡说他很清楚地看到了他
Well, Oscar said he got a good look at him.
为什么要冒险
Why roll the dice?
什么意思
What do you mean?
透露一下
I got a heads up.
洛佩兹是队伍中的第三个
Lopez is gonna be number three in the lineup.
安东尼奥
Antonio, Antonio,
洛佩兹逍遥法外的话会消失去另一座城市
Lopez walks, he'll disappear. He'll hit another city.
他会再次杀人
He will kill again.
第三个
Number three.
这边
Right this way.
奥斯卡  我跟你说
Oscar, I want to tell you something.
里面有六个人
You're gonna see six men in there.
但他们看不到你  所以你不用害怕
But they can't see you, so don't be afraid.
你就只需要...
All you have to do is--
你只需要说实话
All you have to do is tell the truth.
如果你看到那晚开货车的人
If you see the man who was driving the van that night,
就指出来
just point at him.
-好  -好吗
- Okay. - Okay?
这边  孩子
Right this way, son.
孩子  你看到
Son, do you see the man
那晚跟你妈妈在一起的人了吗
who was with your mother the other night?
那个  第一个
That one! Number one!
男孩没有指认出我的客户
For the record, the boy did not identify my client.
奥斯卡  慢慢来  再看看
Oscar, take your time. Look again.
警探
Detective!
奥斯卡  你之前不是这样描述的
Oscar, that's not the way you described him.
他已经做出选择了
He already made his choice.
是他  三号  我确定  就是他
It was him! Number three! I know it was him!
好了  他指认出的是三号嫌疑人
There. Let the record show he pointed to suspect number three.
拜托  警方在胁迫证人
Come on, the policeman's coercing the witness!
不  他刚才没准备好  时间不够
No, he had no time! He wasn't ready!
-行了行了  别吵了  -好
- All right, all right, let's shut it down. - Yep.
我知道指认一事做得不好
Look, I know the ID wasn't perfect.
简直就是灾难
It was a disaster!
我们再想别的办法拿下他
We just find another way to get this guy.
好  什么办法
Okay. How?
我们没有他跟案件相关的任何证据
We got no evidence linking him to the crime.
任何证据都没有
To anything!
法医证据都随着货车炸毁了
The forensics all blew up with the van!
那里的员工  都被遣返了
The employees, they're all being deported!
邻居都因为害怕不敢开口
Neighbors too afraid to talk.
兄弟  我们甚至没有证据
Bro, we don't have enough
申请搜查令搜查他家里
to get a search warrant for his damn house!
那怎么办  就放他走吗
So what? We just let him go?
我们就只有那一次机会
We had one shot!
-结果被我们毁了  -不
- We blew it. - No.
你就这么走了吗
You're just gonna walk away?
要让洛佩兹那个人渣赢吗
Let this punk Lopez win?
我找基科
Looking for Chico.
你是谁
Who the hell are you?
汉克·博伊特  警察
Hank Voight. I'm police.
我跟你无话可说  兄弟
Yeah? Well, I got nothing to say, homie.
我不是因你而来
Look, I'm not here about you.
而是因为你妹妹莫妮卡
I'm here about your sister Monica.
他们一直没找到杀她的凶手
They never found the guy who killed her.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
那是因为你们根本不在乎非法移民
That's 'cause you guys don't care about illegals.
我们出去走走
So let's take a walk.
干什么
For what?
我想跟你说说我们调查的进展
I'd like to update you on the status of our investigation.
好
All right.
这是你的新家
This is your new home, buddy.
-我会来看你  -你保证吗
- I'll come visit. - Do you promise?
我保证
I promise.
去吧
Go on.
真的很感谢你收留他
Thank you so much for taking him.
如果他有任何需要
And if he needs anything--
或者你有任何需要  给我打电话  好吗
or you--anything, you call, okay?
-谢谢  -不客气
- Gracias. - De nada.
证据
莫妮卡
这是在停尸房找到的
This was at the morgue.
后面刻着莫妮卡的名字
Monica's name is engraved on the back.
我觉得应该交给你
I thought you should have it.
谢谢
Thank you.
那个警察之前来过  他为什么不带过来
The policeman that was here, why didn't he bring it?
哪个警察
Which policeman?
他说他叫汉克
He said his name was Hank.
他来找你了吗
He came to talk to you?
不  他找了我侄子基科
No. Chico, my nephew.
什么时候的事
When was this?
昨晚
Last night.
汉克  是我  我们需要马上谈谈
Hank, it's me. We need to talk right away.
拜托拜托拜托
Come on, come on, come on.
汉克  还是我  给我回电
Hank, it's me again. Call me!
金  去洛佩兹家  我马上过去
Kim, meet me at Lopez's house! I'm headed there now!
芝加哥警署
Chicago PD!
洛佩兹
Lopez!
安东尼奥
Antonio?
杀死强奸犯
怎么回事
What the hell happened?
你想这样  安东尼奥
You wanted this to happen, Antonio.
你只是不敢承认
You're just afraid to admit it.
你为什么还没睡
Why are you still up?
在写大学论文
Working on my college essay.
凉掉了
It's cold.
抱歉  我工作上有事
Sorry. I got stuck at work.
我们找到杀害那个女人的凶手了
We found the guy who killed that woman.
格洛莉亚
Gloria.
那好  好事
Good. That's good.
我要去睡了
I'm gonna go to bed.
你想听听我目前写好的吗
Want to hear what I wrote so far?
好啊
Yeah, yeah.
好  我祖母自多米尼加共和国
Okay, so, "My grandmother came
那时她没有接受过教育
"From the Dominican Republic with no education,
没钱  没家
"No money, and no family.
她就只有一个梦想
"All she had was a dream.
她的梦想就是我
"And her dream was me.
她当时根本不认识我  因为我还没出生
"She didn't even know me, because I wasn't even born,
但我就是她的梦想
"Yet I am the dream she had.
是她一直那么努力的原因
The one she worked so hard for."
就写了这么多
That's all I have so far.
这是个好的开篇
That's a really good start.